# ANNETTE CLIFF

annettecliff.work@gmail.com Portfolio Link Schedule A Call https://www.linkedin.com/in/annette-cliff/

#### **Web Developer**

Seasoned developer with experience in creating custom websites, demonstrated expertise in A/B testing, accessibility, cross-browser compatibility, theme development, and front-end technologies. Effective in project management and collaboration, delivering results while meeting clients' needs and expectations. Experienced in working at fast paced agencies, having worked with over twenty-five clients.

# EXPERIENCE

# Web Developer - Fuel Made January 2022 - May 2023

- Conducted Google Optimize A/B tests, resulting in a 40% average improvement in conversion rate and revenue per session.
- Managed design and functionality updates for eight clients' Shopify themes with various theme versions.
- Developed three custom Shopify themes using the latest development practices, including JSON templates, completed two weeks early.
- Streamlined project workflow and provided project managers with valuable links for QA review, communicated daily using Slack, Asana, Figma.
- Provided estimates for varying sized tasks and documented development and custom CMS settings with screen casts post production.

#### Web Engineer - Lemonade Creative October 2019 - December 2021

- Oversaw daily updates for over seventeen clients, covering design, functionality, research, app integration, and version control using Git.
- Communicated project updates with project managers and clients using ActiveCollab, Google Suite, Zoom.
- Designed custom Shopify themes for seven clients, adhering to best practices and a pre-configured design system.
- Implemented metafields for three Headless sites, gaining experience with Styled Components, GraphQL, Gatsby.js.
- Proficient in various CMS platforms, including Contentful, Shopify, WordPress.

# Web Intern - Lettuce Entertain You Enterprises June 2019 - August 2019

- Maintained SEO, ADA compliance, SSL, SMS, and email templates for over one hundred national restaurant brands' websites.
- Demonstrated leadership and teamwork skills while coordinating with a group of five interns on a restaurant concept project.
- Attended weekly seminars, gained understanding of restaurant management, expense reporting.
- Collaborated with a team of three developers using Git and Bitbucket for version control.
- Customized the WordPress back-end, applied styles, and deployed updates using AWS for a new website, Whole30Delivered.

# **SKILLS**

# Communication

• ActiveCollab, Asana, Customer Service, Google Suite, Notion, Polish Language, Project Management, Risk Management, Slack, Zoom

# **Technical**

• Adobe Creative Suite, Contentful, Google Optimize, Google Suite, Figma, InVision, Microsoft Office Suite, Shopify, WordPress

# **Web Development**

• A/B Testing, AWS, Bitbucket, CSS3, Git, GitHub, GraphQL, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, Liquid, MySQL, PHP, QA

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Arts in Graphic and Web Design - Minneapolis College of Art and Design, Minnesota 2020

Bachelor of Arts in Communication, Minor in Arts in Media - University of Minnesota Duluth, Minnesota 2018

Intensive Study Abroad - Jagiellonian University, Poland Summer 2015

# CERTIFICATIONS

**Meta Front-End Developer - Professional Certificate** (in progress)